A killer. A cop. Someone's... buried alive.
Oxygen is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Richard Shepard.
When housewife Frances Hannon is abducted and buried alive,
detective Madeline Foster is brought in.
With only 24 hours before Frances' oxygen runs out, Madeline pursues the
trail laid by a killer calling himself Harry Houdini.
After capturing him, Madeline brings Harry back to the police station, but
is unable to get him to confess where Frances is buried.
As time runs down, Harry gets inside the head of unstable, alcoholic Madeline.
Det. Madeline Foster, played by Maura Tierney.
Harry, played by Adrien Brody.
Clark Hannon, played by James Naughton.
Frances Hannon, played by Laila Robins.
Tim, played by Terry Kinney.
Jesse, played by Paul Calderon.
Oxygen is a 1999 thriller film, directed and written by Richard Shepard.
The film follows a troubled cop, Madeline Foster (Maura Tierney) as she
pursues a kidnapper who calls himself Harry Houdini (Adrien Brody).
The film was shot on location in New York City.
The film explores themes of new york city, death
penalty, miami, florida, ransom, kidnapping.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.